Guide to the Van Austin Harvey Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Van Austin Harvey papers
1952-2007
SC1000
Harvey, Van Austin
2 Linear feet
Collection includes correspondence with Rudolf Bultmann, 1960-73, Schubert Ogden, 1960-61, D. Z. Phillips, 2004, 2006, and Alvin Plantinga, 1997-98; a radio script, “The Academy Awards,” prepared by Harvey and Bob Batchelder for Religion at the News Desk broadcast over WELI in New Haven, CT, March 22, 1952; bound copy of his dissertation “Myth, Faith, and History”; and examples of his published work including reprints, journal issues, and books.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Van A. Harvey, 2010.
Biographical/Historical note
Professor of Religious Studies at Stanford University since 1978, Harvey trained at Yale Divinity School and taught at the University of Pennsylvania before coming to Stanford.
Scope and Contents note
Collection includes correspondence with Rudolf Bultmann, 1960-73, Schubert Ogden, 1960-61, D. Z. Phillips, 2004, 2006, and Alvin Plantinga, 1997-98; a radio script, “The Academy Awards,” prepared by Harvey and Bob Batchelder for Religion at the News Desk broadcast over WELI in New Haven, CT, March 22, 1952; bound copy of his dissertation “Myth, Faith, and History”; and examples of his published work including reprints, journal issues, and books.
Access Terms
Bultmann, Rudolf Karl, 1884-1765.; Ogden, Schubert Miles, 1928-; Phillips, D. Z., (Dewi Zephaniah); Plantinga, Alvin.; Religion--Study and teaching.; Stanford University--Faculty.
Collection Contents
- Papers and publications, 1952-2007; Accession ARCH-2010-109
  - Bultmann, Rudolf – correspondence, photocopies, [partly in German], 1960-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ogden, Schubert – correspondence [partly in German], 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Phillips, D. Z. – correspondence and Harvey’s memorial address, 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Plantinga, Alvin – correspondence and chapter text, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Colloquium on Kaufman’s Systematic Theology – invitation letter and Harvey’s text, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Harvey, “The Proper Task of Theology: Seven Theses”, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Radio script, “The Academy Awards,” prepared by Harvey and Bob Batchelder for Religion at the News Desk broadcast over WELI in New Haven, CT, 1952 March (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harvey and Ogden, “How New is the ‘New Quest of the Historical Jesus’?” – mimeographed article with German reprint, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Harvey, reprints, 1959-2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Harvey’s CV and biographical sketch by Charley Hardwick (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Harvey, “Myth, Faith, and History” – carbon copy of dissertation (bound) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stanford publications by Harvey (Sandstone and Tile article 1998; interview in Humanist Forum newsletter 1995) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photocopied articles (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Published works in journals and magazines, including: Perkins School of Theology Journal, 1958-88; Religion in Life, 1952-64; Theology Today 1958-64; Free Inquiry 1985-2007; The Christian Century, 1965-2000; Religious Education, 1954, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Harvey, Van A. Theologische Begriffe, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Books with chapters by Harvey: Theology at the End of Modernity (1991); Can Religion Be Explained Away? (1996); Il Problema de Dio Nella Teologia Americana Contemporanea (1970); The Historical Jesus and the Kerygmatic Christ (1964); The Future of Philosophical Theology (1971) (Box 2)